SHAKEEL MUGHAL

EX-CHIEF WARRANT OFFICER

Email: smughal009@hotmail.com

Address: House # CB/1742 Street #33 Allama Iqbal Colony

Rawalpindi Cantt, Pakistan

Call @ 00923455037001

00923119555288



Objective:

Highly motivated, methodical, decisive and results-oriented individual seeking a full-time position as a Aerospace Technician/Supervisor, Quality Control / Assurance Inspector, QSHE Executive and in related areas inside a competitive environment where I am allowed to use my potential & experience to best serve the needs of the company as well as allow me to continue develop my knowledge and potential.

Qualification Summary:

More than 25 years' experience in Aerospace (Airframe) Technology as a Maintenance Technician/Supervisor and Quality control Inspector / Supervisor. Considerable knowledge of 1st & 2nd line maintenance (back shop maintenance), Depot Level Maintenance, maintaining and recording of aerospace related documents and practical application of Quality control step by step processes, including applying principles, techniques, procedures, and the use of suitable tools during the production / overhauling phase of various components. Ability to analyze non-conformances / evaluations made during inspection processes and evaluate root causes based on Non-conformances. Capable of providing documentation, records of Quality evaluations, preparing and analyzing information for the purpose of Management Review.

Having good communication and attention to details skill.

Education:

Diploma of Associate Engineer (Mechanical), 1996 MBA (Executive), 2018

Professional Course

Field Training Detachment (1996)
Quality Assurance Programme (2004)
Maintenance Supervisory course (2009)
Internal Audit Techniques (DAS) (2016)
Military Leadership & Command Course (2016)
Risk Assessment Technique and Internal Auditing (IDEAS) (2017)
Occupational Health and Safety course "OHSAS 18001-2007" (2017)
Non Destructive Testing Level I (Ultrasonic Testing) (2018)
Fire Safety Management (2019)
NEBOSH IGC in Occupational Health and safety (2020)
MS Office

Work Experience:

1. Aerospace Quality Control / Assurance / H&S, Aircraft Rebuild Factory 2011-2020

Responsibilities included: performing a variety of inspections / Evaluations of components of Aircrafts during in-phase and out-phase process. Including

· Monitoring and auditing of products to ensure high standards of quality.

 Ensuring that all QA/QC Tests are carried out on time and in full. Provide weekly and monthly reports to senior managers on performance.

Performs regular in-process inspections and checks adhering to quality inspection

procedures and work processes.

- Carry out visual inspections and verify test result of various treatment processes against the established standards.
- Inspects purchased parts and materials for conformity to standards, specifications, and processing requirements.
- Preparing and analyzing information for the purpose of Management Review and to prepare their corresponding minutes and to ensure they are distributed timely at all level.
- Making sure that all QA records, data & information are available to managers.

Responsible for the review and update of the programmed quality plans.

Responsible for Ground safety activities according to set goals and standards.

Supervising all regulatory compliance activities and helping to enforce quality control
policies and best practice principals covering the safety, production and inspection
according to Quality Management system (AS-9100 Rev D).

Maintaining a Portfolio of QA/QC related reports / Evaluations for the perusal and record

of External Auditor and management as well.

2. Aircraft Maintenance Technician/ supervisor, PAF Base Samungli (2007-11)

- First line inspection, maintenance and documentation as per required and given standard and SOPs.
- Front Desk Management and A/C documentation.
- Keeping a record and Tracking of all life components up to date.
- Maintaining and tracking of all schedule and unscheduled inspections of aircraft.

3. Research & Library and Inspection Cell (A/C spares, components and related test Equipment), 103 ALC (1998-2006)

- Maintaining and updating of all IPCs and TOs related to MIR-III & V, Falcon, ALT-III and Mushak A/Cs.
- Identification of unidentified items related to A/C spares, parts and components.
- Inspection and verification of all incoming & outgoing stores related to aircraft spare/ parts and test equipments according to set SOPs and standard.
- Tracking and maintaining the Rejected items as per SOPs.

4. Airframe Accy Shop, Aircraft rebuild Factory PAC Kamra (1996-1998)

- Repair / overhauling of Hydraulic, Pneumatic and fuel components of Chinese origin A/C.
- Documentation and tracking of Life components